# QI JIA (JERRY) SUN

3646 Lynndale Cresecent Burnaby, B.C. V5A 3S8 qjsun@sfu.ca \(\phi\) qijiasunjerry@gmail.com

### PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

Java, Python, HTML, CSS, MATLAB, R, LATEX

#### **PROJECTS**

## A Machine Learning Analysis of Features in Deceptive and Credible News

Fake news is a pervasive crisis in the media. Over the past two years, mass communication via social media has magnified the impact and influence of misinformation. This project seeks to find a machine learning classifier that can determine the validity of news based on the word distributions and specific linguistic and stylistic differences of the first few words. Using this classifier, the linguistic and stylistic features of fake news were also identified.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## SFU Computational Linguistics Lab

June 2018-Present

Research Assistant

Collaborated with Prof. Maite Taboada and Dr. Fatemeh Torabi Asr on a fake news classification project. I participated in weekly lab meetings and worked in a team to research topics such as sentiment analysis. Made contribution in analyzing fact checkers and their compatibility for text extraction. Also made contributions in data annotation and collection and was cited in this paper http://aclweb.org/anthology/W18-5502. Currently in the process of publishing a paper.

# SFU Research with Prof. Veselin Jungic

April 2019 - Present

Research Assistant

Conducted research with Prof. Veselin Jungic on Van der Waerden's theorem, a branch of Ramsey Theory.

## ACADEMIC ACHIEVEMENTS

**Team Canada Top 30**, Intel International Science and Engineering Fair (IISEF, the world's premier science fair competition); currently in contention for Top 8 and eligibility to compete at IISEF (May 2019)

International Geography Olympiad 2019 Participant 1 of 4 students representing Team Canada in the International Geography Olympiad in Hong Kong

National Top 20 and B.C. Champion in both 2017 and 2018, Canadian Geographic Challenge. UBC Statistics Award 2019 Best statistics project at the Greater Vancouver Regional Science Fair for A Machine Learning Analysis of Features in Deceptive and Credible News

Greater Vancouver Regional Science Fair Bronze Medal (April 2018)

# **EDUCATION**

Simon Fraser University
Concurrent studies student
Burnaby Mountain Secondary School
Secondary School Education

September 2018 - Present

September 2015 - Present Overall GPA: 96.3